CURRICULUM VITAE KIRUI ENID CHELANGAT

P.O. Box 9387 - 00200 NAIROBI, Cell: 0725990978, E-mail: enidkirui@gmail.com

PERSONAL DETAILS

NATIONALITY: Kenyan
SEX: Female

Date of birth: 17th/09/85
Religion: Christian

PROFILE

I am an ambitious Quality and Regulatory Affairs Professional with unwavering resolve. I am determined to do well in my job and have a successful career, as well as to make the organization I work for more competitive. Pride myself in being strongly reliable and focused quality assurance and regulatory affairs professional; with a great depth and breadth of cross regional experience in pharmaceutical and cosmetics product review and evaluation with over 9 years of experience.

I am someone who believes that learning is a process that never stops and to be productive one must always be ready to improve their skills

KEY SKILLS

- Regulatory Knowledge
- Quality management systems
- Excellent Organization skills
- Working effectively with diverse group of people
- Business acumen
- Pro-activeness and Results oriented
- Strong communication skills

EDUCATION

April 2006- May 2009: **JomoKenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology**

• Undergraduate degree in BSc. Medical microbiology, (Second class, lower division)

2000-2003 Buruburu girls' secondary school

• Grade B-(Minus) in Kenya certificate of secondary Education (KCSE).

1994-1999 Tengecha girls boarding primary school

• Kenya certificate of primary Education.

EXPERIENCE

Aug. 2021 to Current: L'Oreal East Africa Limited POSITION: Regulatory and Public Affairs Manager

RESPONSIBILITIES:

June 2017 to July 2021: Beiersdorf East Africa Limited POSITION: Regulatory affairs & Quality Assurance Specialist RESPONSIBILITIES

- Ensuring the regulatory compliance for all Beiersdorf products for all countries in the Management Unit (MU) CEWA (Central East and West Africa).
- Working closely with global R&D and Marketing departments during product launch and relaunch to ensure market regulations are met.
- Advising the business in case of regulatory developments that might affect the business positively or negatively.
- Coordinating the approval, registration, listing or notification of Beiersdorf consumer products to ensure fast access to market in the CEWA countries.
- Support in label development to ensure compliance with each country regulations.
- Coordinating samples submissions from various manufacturing sites to approved laboratories as per importing country requirements.
- Maintained and indexed correspondence and approved documentation on drug products, archiving copies of submitted files.
- Representing the company in various forums such KAM and KEBs technical committee influencing regulatory decision that will affect the company's business.
- On shelf products assessments and reporting of results to relevant stakeholders.
- Management of VAS (Value Added Services) activities and LSP (Logistics Service Providers) to include monitoring of warehousing of products from other countries.
- Support documentation requirements of various quality, compliance, certification and accreditation programs such as ISO 9001
- Review gap analysis and reviews of Product and Process requirements, Non-Conforming product / process Handling process; set controls and tracking throughout the cycle.
- Track corrective and preventive actions for manufacturing problems & gaps.
- Keep a track on Continual Improvement projects from project identification, risk assessments, implementation to post implementation evaluation.
- Coordinating internal and external audit and follow up of findings to ensure closure and ensuring sustained improvements.
- Supplier management on quality aspects.
- Supporting the supply chain team in setting up procedures and guidelines for effective Quality Management Systems
- Coordinating change management
- Complaints management

September 2013 to June 2017: Bimeda Limited

POSITION: Regulatory affairs Coordinator (AMEA) RESPONSIBILITIES

- Facilitating new product registration for Africa, Middle East and Asian (AMEA) market and update any product registrations, in line with change requests, so as to safeguard business continuity.
- Ensure high quality collaboration between headquarters Regulatory (Global Regulatory Affairs) and development functions; Area Regulatory Head and local Regulatory teams to deliver the fastest regulatory approvals.
- Identifying as early as possible, the required documentation and any content, quality and/or timeline issues. Negotiate the delivery of approved technical source documents in accordance with project timeline.
- Support AMEA Commercial objectives for new and existing products. Ensure alignment of Regulatory objectives with global development strategies and commercial plans
- Evaluating key issues for discussion and negotiated with Health Authority experts to clarity questions.
- Coordinating with Bimeda colleagues in various countries to ensure that all the documentation and samples requirements of each country is obtained and delivered.
- Requested data from the manufacturing site and submitted the updated version of the dossier to Competent Authorities.
- Putting requests to KEBS for approval
- Arranged and indexed correspondence and approved documentation on drug products, archiving copies of submitted files
- Assist in the continuous improvement of departmental systems to support the regulatory function.
- Ensuring all legal and regulatory documents concerning the company and products are up to date in all drug regulatory registration.
- Represent the company in various forums e.g. KAPI, PPB, AAK, PCPB.
- Assist in managing product incidents and support product recalls.
- Report and follow-up on product complaints with manufacturing sites, customers, commercial teams and conduct analysis of product complaint trends in conjunction with the Medical department.
- Review, update and finalize all distributor quality agreements at renewals.

Jan 2011 to Aug. 2013: Current: Laboratory and Allied limited.

POSITION: Drug Registration Officer.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Timely Preparation of dossiers for registration in Kenya and other countries as per the outlined format and guidelines
- Maintaining progress reports for all RA operations for presentation at meetings and to the management.

- Ensuring that the formulation is consistent with that in Batch Manufacturing record (BMR).
- Ensuring that all legal requirements are adhered to.
- Ensuring that any change after registration is reported to the registrar.
- Assist in responding to queries raised by various regulatory bodies on drug product registration.
- Making sure that follow-up is made in order that re-registration is not delayed.
- Ensuring that there is coordination of registration dossiers with QA and QC department.
- Proper record keeping of all Regulatory documents assigned in a manner that they are retrievable whenever required.

INTERESTS

Reading, travelling, listening to music and doing community volunteer work (Member of Kenya Red Cross society)

REFEREES

1. Dr. George Wafula

Pharmaceutical Supply Chain Manager AAR Health Care, Head Office 4th Ngong Avenue, Williamson House

Cell Phone: 0722-360951 Email: gwangasa@gmail.com

2. Rashid Sheik

Senior Laboratory Scientist Centre for Respiratory diseases

Cell phone: +25472159616 P.O.Box 14984-00100, Nairobi

3. Dr. Castro Wanjoya

Regulatory Affairs Manager (AMEA)

Bimeda

Cell phone: +254721685287 Email: cwanjoya@bimeda.com